Christian Onyeukwu

www.christianonyeukwu.com | Github:christianRibig5 christianonyeukwu@gmail.com | LinkedIn:// christianonyeukwu Sherbrooke QC | 819.919.6872

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Motivated and adaptable software engineer with more than 6 years of full-stack and cloud experience, recently completed an MSc in Computer Science (December 2024) with research focus on real-time reactive systems. Eager to contribute to agile teams across Canada; open to relocation and ready to start immediately.

EDUCATION

BISHOP'S UNIVERSITY

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE Graduated Dec 2024 | Sherbrooke, QC

Thesis: Algebraic/Logical Verification for Real-Time Reactive Systems.

Researcher (2022 - 2024): Investigated formal methods and logic based systems, collaborated with Prof. S. Bruda on reactive System verifications using algebraic models.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming:

•Java•JavaScript•Python•ReactJS•NodeJS•SQL

Frameworks & Tools:

- •Spring Boot Docker Kubernetes Kafka Jenkins Ansible ROS Cloud & DevOPs:
- $\bullet \mathsf{AWS} \bullet \mathsf{Git} \bullet \mathsf{CI} \backslash \mathsf{CD} \ \mathsf{Pipelining} \ \bullet \mathsf{Shell} \ \mathsf{Scripting} \bullet \mathsf{Linux}$

Architecture:

Microservices • REST APIs • Agile • TDD

EXPERIENCE

ECR TECHNOLOGY SERVICES | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aug 2016 - May 2022

- Designed and implemented cloud-based solutions to modernize legacy systems, reducing downtime by 40%.
- Led the development of the QikPharma web application for medication prescriptions, integrating real-time customer feedback loops to continuously improve system accuracy.
- Developed and deployed RESTful APIs using Java Spring Boot and NodeJS, ensuring scalability and security best practices.
- Delivered technical support for critical systems, resolving 90% of escalated issues within SLA timelines.

IMPACT:Improved system reliability and customer satisfaction scores by 35%.

BISHOP'S UNIVERSITY | TEACHING ASSISTANT

Feb 2022 - May 2022

- Grade assignments, quizzes, lab reports, and exams in alignment with the instructor's guidelines.
- Maintain course-related records, such as attendance or grades, and provide constructive feedback to students to help them improve their understanding and performance.

IMPACT: Increased student engagement by 25% through interactive learning techniques

PROJECTS

QIKPHARMA - (MEDICAL PRESCRIPTION MGT. SYSTEM) |

PLANNING LEAD Jan 2021 – May 2022 | ECR Technology Services

- Defined and implemented multi-role workflow paths such as pharmacist, prescription validation, approval and fulfillment.
 - Developed and deployed REST APIs for the backend processes, ensuring scalability and security best practices.

CHIT CHAT | CLASS PROJECT FOR DISTRIBUTED CLIENT-SERVER PROGRAMMING

Apr 2022 - May 2022 | BU, CA

- Lead the development of **Chit Chat**, an anonymous chat application created as a class project.
- Chit Chat provides real-time communication while utilizing a Java backend and ReactJS frontend.

PUBLICATIONS

[1] C. Nworu, E. Ekpenyong, J. Chisimkwuo, C. Onyeukwu, G. Okwara, and O. Agwu. The effects of modified relu activation functions in image classification. *Journal of Biomedical Engineering and Medical Devices*, 2022.

[2] C. Onyeukwu and S. Bruda. Algebraic/logical verification for real-time reactive systems. *Bishop's University, MSc Theses*, 2024.

CERTIFICATIONS

Oracle Certified Associate (OCA), Java SE Programmer, March 2016